<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog of Suresh Kumar Nalluru</title>
    <link>http://blog.nalluru.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Blog of Suresh Kumar Nalluru</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2012-2021 Suresh Kumar Nalluru. All rights reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 23:28:04 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.nalluru.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Git Worktree</title>
      <link>http://blog.nalluru.com/posts/git-worktree/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 23:28:04 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nalluru.com/posts/git-worktree/</guid>
      <description>Use the same git repo and .git content but have multiple working directories. This can be very useful if you are switcing contexts on the same monorepo.
From the documentation explaining the use-case:
 create a temporary linked working tree to make the emergency fix, remove it when done, and then resume your earlier refactoring session.
 $ git worktree add -b emergency-fix ../temp master $ pushd ../temp # ... hack hack hack .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exiftool</title>
      <link>http://blog.nalluru.com/posts/exiftool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 21:10:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nalluru.com/posts/exiftool/</guid>
      <description>exiftool is a wonderful tool if you like custom renaming of files. It also supports HEIC files (the default format for apple iphones) these days. sample usages below.
Rename jpg etc based on DateTimeOriginal exif tag inside the image
exiftool -r &amp;#39;-FileName&amp;lt;DateTimeOriginal&amp;#39; -d %Y/%m/%Y-%m-%d_%H-%M-%S%%-c.%%e -ext JPG -ext PNG -ext jpeg -ext HEIC -ext GIF . For files which dont have DateTimeOriginal tag rename jpg etc based on FileModifyDate
exiftool -r &amp;#34;-FileName&amp;lt;FileModifyDate&amp;#34; -d &amp;#39;Unknown/%%f%%-c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note taking with Nvalt</title>
      <link>http://blog.nalluru.com/posts/nvalt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 18:25:53 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nalluru.com/posts/nvalt/</guid>
      <description>I always used to write tidbits of programming or notes in a file in electronic format and refer to them frequently. Over a span of few montsh this would grow to be a big file that becomes invaluable to me and I end up referring it again and again. A Simple text file with a simple delimiter like &amp;mdash; or ### would have done to job but not always easy to search.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unhide Library Folder In Macos</title>
      <link>http://blog.nalluru.com/posts/2012-09-15-unhide-library-folder-in-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 12:17:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nalluru.com/posts/2012-09-15-unhide-library-folder-in-macos/</guid>
      <description>In MacOS, Every user&amp;rsquo;s home directory has a bunch of sub-directories that are hidden. Though they exist, you cant see them generally with Finder. Whether a particular folder is visible or not is controlled by an extended flag that is set for that directory.
If you simply want to see &amp;lsquo;Library&amp;rsquo; directory (folder) always in the finder, just execute the following commands (in a terminal windows) and you are done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programmers Settings Fonts And Schemes</title>
      <link>http://blog.nalluru.com/posts/programmers-settings-fonts-and-schemes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 12:17:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nalluru.com/posts/programmers-settings-fonts-and-schemes/</guid>
      <description>Being a software person, a fair chunk of my life is spent before the computer. Which translates to the feeling that I should be very comfortable doing my routing tasks with it - The most common task being reading whats shown on the screen..
I consider that Fonts play a very important role in this. A font for a programmer need not by stylish (like the newspaper fonts) but should have the following properties.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
