<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Blog of Suresh Kumar Nalluru</title>
    <link>http://blog.nalluru.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Blog of Suresh Kumar Nalluru</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2012-2017. &lt;br&gt;All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 10:40:32 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.nalluru.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exiftool</title>
      <link>http://blog.nalluru.com/post/2018/04/exiftool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 10:40:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nalluru.com/post/2018/04/exiftool/</guid>
      <description>exiftool is a wonderful tool if you like custom renaming of files. It also supports HEIC files (the default format for apple iphones) these days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note taking with Nvalt</title>
      <link>http://blog.nalluru.com/post/2017/12/note-taking-with-nvalt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 18:25:53 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nalluru.com/post/2017/12/note-taking-with-nvalt/</guid>
      <description>I always used to write tidbits of programming or notes in a file in electronic format and refer to them frequently. Over a span of few montsh this would grow to be a big file that becomes invaluable to me and I end up referring it again and again. A Simple text file with a simple delimiter like &amp;mdash; or ### would have done to job but not always easy to search.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unhide Library Folder In Macos</title>
      <link>http://blog.nalluru.com/post/2017/08/unhide-library-folder-in-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 12:17:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nalluru.com/post/2017/08/unhide-library-folder-in-macos/</guid>
      <description>In MacOS, Every user&amp;rsquo;s home directory has a bunch of sub-directories that are hidden. Though they exist, you cant see them generally with Finder. Whether a particular folder is visible or not is controlled by an extended flag that is set for that directory.
If you simply want to see &amp;lsquo;Library&amp;rsquo; directory (folder) always in the finder, just execute the following commands (in a terminal windows) and you are done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programmers Settings Fonts And Schemes</title>
      <link>http://blog.nalluru.com/post/2017/08/programmers-settings-fonts-and-schemes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 12:17:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nalluru.com/post/2017/08/programmers-settings-fonts-and-schemes/</guid>
      <description>Being a software person, a fair chunk of my life is spent before the computer. Which translates to the feeling that I should be very comfortable doing my routing tasks with it - The most common task being reading whats shown on the screen..
I consider that Fonts play a very important role in this. A font for a programmer need not by stylish (like the newspaper fonts) but should have the following properties.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>